

I am a solutions-oriented developer with a passion for great user experience. I believe technology should be enjoyable and easy to use! While I excel at solving problems on my own, I am most fulfilled when collaborating with others to find solutions.

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Email: Cathy347Le@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://www.cathyle.dev
Github: https://github.com/Cathy347Le

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cathyxle

Location: Washington, DC Phone: (408) 390-5534

WORK:

GMMB

Website with parallax, animations, and hover effects

Lunar New Year Jeopardy

Self-scoring trivia game utilizing JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, HTML, and CSS

Think Movie

Web app to store personalized movie lists. Built with MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, and Node.js.

Petz

Social media web app for pets. Users can create a profile for their pets, post comments, and "lick" other pet profiles. Built with React, MongoDB, Express, and Node.js.

2018 Senate Elections Map

Recreating the election map using D3.js and React

FRONT END SKILLS:

- HTML, CSS, Sass
- ¡Query, JavaScript, React, AJAX
- Grunt, Bootstrap, Materialize

BACK END SKILLS:

- PHP, Wordpress
- Node, Express
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- RESTful API

ADDITIONAL SKILLS.

- Version Control (Git/Github)
- SourceTree, Codeship
- Responsive Web Design
- MVC Methodology
- Accessibility (WCAG)
- Asana, Slack

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

SOCIAL DRIVER

Maintenance Developer | April 2021 - July 2021 Web Developer | July 2020 - April 2021 Jr Web Developer | July 2019 - July 2020

- Worked with a team of strategists, UX developers, project managers, and visual designers to develop and launch over 18 websites using Wordpress, PHP, HTML, Sass, and JavaScript
- Wrote scripts to clean and migrate the data from client's old Wordpress site to redesigned Wordpress site
- Structured backend using PHP and Javascript to set up custom post types, input fields, and taxonomies
- Implemented custom user-friendly front-end components to empower clients to built their own page content
- Created asset boards, documentation, and conducted CMS trainings for clients to ensure the best user experience
- Maintained websites by fixing bugs, optimizing images, updating plugins and code to improve accessibility, responsiveness, and cross-browser performance while providing a friendly customer service attitude towards clients

GENERAL ASSEMBLY (GA) Software Engineering Immersive | Jan 2019 - April 2019

• Three-month full stack development program focused on common best practices in OOP and MVC frameworks.

GREENBERG QUINLAN ROSNER

Research Data Analyst | May 2018 - Jan 2019 Lead Research Data Associate | Jan 2016 - May 2018 Research Data Associate | Nov 2013 -Dec 2015

- Designed and conducted public opinion research, supervised survey fielding, and programmed over 120 political surveys
- Advised analysts and calling house vendors on best practices to achieve accurate, quality survey data

THE FELDMAN GROUP

Data Specialist | March 2013 - Oct 2013 Research Assistant | Oct 2011 - Feb 2013

• Reviewed, programmed, tested, and monitored over 50 political surveys to ensure accuracy and quality

EDUCATION:

GENERAL ASSEMBLY (GA)

Software Engineering Immersive | Jan 2019 - April 2019

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA: SAN DIEGO

B.A Political Science/American Politics | Class of 2010